# CRISTIAN WILGENHOFF

# Summary

Senior Software Engineer specialised in JavaScript.

Having worked in the tech industry since late 2010 for companies such as Microsoft, Deloitte, US Bank, Best Buy and Bally Technologies, I aim to bring diverse experience and add fruitful value in a role where I can take real software development ownership.

I prefer to work on real and exciting products with active involvement from clients alongside a self-driven team from which I can add value and learn from.

## Information

Name: Cristian Wilgenhoff

• Location: London, UK

E-mail: cpwilgenhoff@gmail.com
 Website: <a href="http://cwilgenhoff.github.io/">http://cwilgenhoff.github.io/</a>
 Github: <a href="https://github.com/cwilgenhoff">https://github.com/cwilgenhoff</a>

• Phone: 07493 074226

# **Key Skills**

Languages: JavaScript (ES6)

JS Static Type Checkers: Flow, Typescript

• Libraries/APIs: React and Redux

• Frameworks: Node, Express, Socket.IO, Angular

Testing Tools: Jest, Enzyme, Karma, MochaJS, Chai, Sinon, Jasmine.

• DB/Storage: PouchDB, CouchDB, MongoDB

Continuous Integration: Buildkite, Jenkins, Travis and CircleCl

• Cloud: Docker, Kubernetes, OpenShift, AWS, Heroku

# Experience

# Engine | Transformation, Full Stack Engineer (Contract)

February 2018 – Present

- Part of a team helping Marine Management Organisation (MMO) to deliver a catch recording platform.
- **Technologies**: React, Node, Typescript, Hapi, Kubernetes.

#### Red Badger, Software Engineer

Jun 2017 - February 2018

- Part of a consulting team helping mayor high street banks in UK to deliver several products:
  - o Authentication Hub (POC): 2-factor biometric authentication for mobile banking applications.
  - o International Payments: Re-vamp of online banking international payments.
  - Open Banking (Corporate Customer Base): UK government bank regulation.
    - Various tasks ranged from creating an initial structure and development of features
      for the frontend to the creation/modification of a vast range of micro-services with
      different capabilities such as connectivity to different LDAP servers, DB2 databases
      and fraud systems along with the creation of pipelines and infrastructure.
  - o Credit Cards App (Retail): Allows retail customers to apply for credit cards.
    - Single Page App with server-side rending. Layered microservices architecture. Node Gateway.
- Continuously cultivate the relationship and skillset of the client.

Technologies: React, Node, Typescript, Spring Boot, Swift, Open Shift, IBM API Connect and Jenkins.

#### FarmDrop, Software Engineer

March 2016 - June 2017

- Part of the customer facing team in charge of building a marketplace for locally sourced food.
- Tasks included adding features fast, migrating legacy Angular components into React, major rebrandings of the shop and several improvements of the current code base through the introduction of standard best practices such as a testing infrastructure for the front-end components using tools like Enzyme. Server-side rendering from a node server.
- Technologies: JS (ES6), React, Redux, Node, Webpack, Jest, Enzyme, Ruby on Rails, Redis.

## Contentment, Software Engineer

Nov 2015 - Feb 2016

- Part of the development team in charge of building a Reader app; a Cordova application built entirely in React acting as a proxy for downloading magazine publications from AWS.
- Worked designing the structure of the app from scratch in a way to load content dynamically.
- Technologies: JS (ES6), React, Node, RxJS, PouchDB.

## Making Sense LLC, Software Engineer

May 2014 – Nov 2015

- Project: Budget Maestro Contractor for Centage Software Engineer
  - o Part of the development team in charge of building Budget Maestro. An application that provides budgeting solutions for companies.
  - o **Technologies**: Angular, Node, MongoDB.
- Project: BCP Contractor for Mobiguity, Inc Software Engineer
  - Responsible and part of the development team of BCP (Behavior Change Platform) a Healthcare product.
  - o **Technologies**: *Node, Express, Angular, MongoDB.*

2012 - 2013

- Project: Migration of Desktop App Contractor for EasySoft USA Software Engineer
  - o **Technologies**: Dojo Toolkit, JavaScript
- Project: Best Buy Store Contractor for migration.mobi Software Engineer
- Project: <u>Cash+ Visa Card</u> Contractor for migration.mobi Software Engineer

#### Globant, Software Engineer

2011 - 2014

- Project: TV Chip Recognition Contractor for Bally Technologies Software Engineer
- Project: Internal Intranet Contractor for Deloitte Software Engineer

### Southworks, SharePoint Developer

2010 - 2011

- Project: PDC 2010 (Deployment) Contractor for Microsoft SharePoint Developer
- Project: KEXP (CMS for Streams) Contractor for KEXP Radio SharePoint Developer

#### Freelance

#### PandemSim – Freelance POC for University of Ohio - Software Engineer

Feb 2015 – April 2015

- During the first quarter of 2015, I worked as a freelancer for the University of Ohio to develop a PoC aiming to perform pandemics simulations. This stage only involved basic CRUD operations of models.
- Technologies: Node, Angular, Express, MongoDB and Socket.IO.

## Education

2006 - 2014

### **Systems Engineering**

National University of Central Buenos Aires (UNICEN) - Buenos Aires